Guide to James R. Hoffa Documentation collection, 1954-1976 LAC0005
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
James R. Hoffa Documentation collection
1934-2011
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
LAC0005
12 Linear Feet 11 document boxes, 3 over-sized flat box
The collection contains newspaper clippings, magazine articles, trial transcripts, publicity materials, copies of congressional hearings, photographs, videocassettes, vinyl records and audio tapes. This material covers a variety of background materials on James R. Hoffa, covering the time period from 1956, when Hoffa was Vice President of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, past his disappearance in 1975 to the election of his son, James Hoffa Jr., as General-President of the Teamsters.
Historical/Biographical note
James R. Hoffa (1913- ) was an American labor union leader and former President of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters. Hoffa was born in Brazil, Indiana in 1913. He left school at the age of 14 in 1927 and began full-time manual labor to help support his family. Hoffa had begun his career with the Teamsters as a union organizer in Detroit in the early 1930s, where he became president of Local 299. He was first elected Vice President in 1952 and later served as the union's General President from 1958 to 1971. He secured the first national agreement for teamsters' rates in 1964, and played a major role in the growth and development of the union, which eventually became the largest single union in the United States.
Prior to Hoffa's election, the Teamsters and his predecessor, Dave Beck, had become the focus of a congressional investigation by the Senate Select Committee on Improper Activities in the Labor or Management Field, which was chaired by Senator McClellan from Arkansas. The chief counsel of the committee was Robert F. Kennedy. The investigations against the Teamsters and Hoffa continued throughout the late 1950s and early 1960s, and Hoffa was repeatedly called to testify before the McClellan committee, which charged him with a wide range of improper and illegal activities, including use of union funds for personal purposes, corruption, and perjury. In 1964 Hoffa was convicted and began serving his sentences in federal prison in Lewisburg, Pennsylvania.
In 1971, President Nixon issued a conditional pardon for Hoffa, releasing him from prison under the condition that he remained inactive in union management. Hoffa then worked on a variety of issues, in including a campaign for prison reform, but retained a relatively low profile, while working on a comeback at the local level. On July 30, 1975, he disappeared under mysterious circumstances at the Machus Red Fox restaurant in a Detroit suburb. He married Josephine Poszywak in 1936. The couple had two children: a daughter, Barbara Ann, and a son, James.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The provenance of the collection is not entirely clear. The materials came to the LHRC in two boxes, which were labeled "JRH Personnel." and most likely originated from different departments at the IBT headquarters, possibly from the library, the public relations and press office, the General President's office, and the legal department.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Separated Materials
Proceedings, Eastern Conference of Teamsters, 1954.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains newspaper clippings, magazine articles, trial transcripts, publicity materials, and copies of congressional hearings. This material covers a variety of background materials on James R. Hoffa, covering the time period from 1956, when Hoffa was Vice President of the International Brotherhood of Teamsters, until his disappearance in 1975. it also includes documents for the James R. Hoffa Memorial Scholarship fund from 2008-2011.
Arrangement
Organized into 10 series: Media, Addresses and speeches, IBT press releases, IBT publicity materials, Transcript of Joint Council meeting, Congressional hearings and investigations, Trial documentation, Subject files, Re-printed and photocopied materials, and Unpublished materials.
Labor; Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Beck, Dave; Hoffa, James R. (James Riddle)
- Media, 1934-2005; Series 1
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains media coverage of James R. Hoffa and his work with the IBT, as well as coverage of the investigations and following trials against him. Included in the series are newspaper clippings, magazine and journal articles, transcripts from TV and radio shows, audio cassettes, Vinyl records, VHS tapes, and wire reports. The materials, which are arranged chronologically, are covering the time period from 1956 until 1975, and include shorter notices, as well as extensive background analyses and journalistic investigations. The media coverage is on a range of issues including his ascent to the Presidency of the IBT, the exclusion of the IBT from the AFL-CIO after his election as President, the investigations of JRH and the Teamsters by the McClellan commission, spearheaded by its counsel, Robert F. Kennedy, the initiative for a National Master Freight Agreement, the trials against JRH in Nashville, Chattanooga, and Chicago, his imprisonment in 1967, Richard's Nixon's parole for Hoffa before Christmas, 1971, Hoffa's campaign for prison reform, and finally his mysterious disappearance in 1975. It also includes pieces on Hoffa's positions on a variety of labor and economic issues at the time, including collective bargaining, unemployment, automation, and income tax reform. In addition, it includes some media reports focusing more generally on organizing drives and political initiatives of the IBT.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Newspaper Articles Involving the Teamsters, 1934-2005; Series 1; Subseries 1; 2 Linear Feet
    Documents in this subseries have been aranged chronologically.
    The contents of this subseries are made up of newspaper articles pertaining to James R. Hoffa and Roy Lee Williams term as Teamstrs chief. Contents are dated between 1934-2005.
    - 'Scores Rushed to Hospitals in Mill City as Battle Breaks out in Strike Area,' St. Paul Dispatch, May 22, 1934; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Leominster Daily Enterprise, Vol. LX, No. 55, February 9, 1955; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - 'Jimmy Hoffa Fights for Presidency of Teamster Union,' The Detroit News, Vol. 85, No. 53, October 14, 1957; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - 'Enthronement Day for Hoffa', Daily News, Vol. 88, no. 314, July 2, 1961; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - 'Nixon Frees Jimmy Hoffa', Daily News, Vol. 53, No. 156, December 24, 1971; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - 'Teamsters' Williams Describes Road to Top,' The Daily Star-Journal, Vol LXIX, No. 68, May 14, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - 'Hoffa Took Young Williams Under His Wing', The Daily Star-Journal, Vol LXIX, No. 69, May 15, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - 'Teamster President Chosen,' Las Vegas Review, Vol. 77, No. 35, May 16, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - 'Williams Elected Teamsters Chief,' Las Vegas Sun clipping, May 16, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - 'New Union Chief Challenged,' Las Vegas Sun clipping, May 17, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - ''Deals' will Gauge Williams' Power,' The Kansas City Star, May 24, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 'Teamsters Chief Charges, Feds Lied to Senate,' Las Vegas Sun, Vol. 31, No. 319, May 24, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 'Controversy Pursues New Teamster Chief,' Chicago Tribune clipping, May 27, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 'Jake McCarthy: A Personal Opinion. Inside the Teamsters,' St. Louis Post-Dispatch clipping, May 28, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - 'Teamsters Boss Ethics Attacked,' Las Vegas Review Journal, May 28, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - 'Court Tackles Hughes Battle,' Las Vegas Review-Journal, June 1, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 'Williams Shoo-In Despite Indictment, Mob Rumors,' Las Vegas Sun, June 1, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 'Teamsters Chief Rips into Feds,' The Valley Times, Vol 36, No. 333, June 2, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 'Teamsters Vote in Williams,' Las Vegas Review Journal, Vol. 77, No. 55, June 5, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 'Williams Elected President of Teamsters as Rebels Throw Convention into Uproar', 'Teamster Chief Wiretapped in Skimming Probe,' Los Angeles Times clipping, June 5, 1981; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Newspaper, various Teamster topics, 1991; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - The Star-Ledger: Election Special, November 7, 2001; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Investor's Business Daily, Vol. 22, No. 75, July 26, 2005; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - 'Unions Bolt AFL-CIO,' Chicago Tribune, No. 207, July 26, 2005; Series 1 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Random Lengths, 2008 May 2-15; LAC 0005 Series 1 Subseries 1 (Box 15)
    - The Record Business: SJ Teamsters Get Hoffa's Support, 1998 June 12; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - USA Today (photocopy), 2001 August 3; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 1 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Weekly World News: Jimmy Hoffa Found Dead, 1995 September 12; LAC 0005 Series 1; Subseries 1 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings Scrapbook Documenting Teamster Conflict, April 1955 - March 1957; Series 1; 2 Linear Feet Over-sized flat box (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Media 1956, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Media 1957, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Media 1958, Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Media 1959 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Media 1959 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Media 1960 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Media 1960 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Media 1961 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Media 1961 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Media 1962 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Media 1962 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Media 1963 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Media 1963 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Media 1964 [1/5], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Media 1964 [2/5], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Media 1964 [3/5], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Media 1964 [4/5], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Media 1964 [5/5], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Media 1965, Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Media 1966 [1/3], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Media 1966 [2/3], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Media 1966 [3/3], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Media 1967 [1/4], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Media 1967 [2/4], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Media 1967 [3/4], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Media 1967 [4/4], Series 1 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Media 1968, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Media 1969, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Media 1970 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Media 1970 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Media 1971 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Media 1971 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Media 1972 [1/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Media 1972 [2/2], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Media 1973, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Media 1974, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Media 1975 [1/4], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Media 1975 [2/4], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Media 1975 [3/4], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Media 1975 [4/4], Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Media 1976, Series 1 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Interview: President Hoffa At University of California, N.D.; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Film And Book Ideas, 1964; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Clippings and Articles, 1963-1974; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Pro Hoffa Material And News Clippings, 1957-1963; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Clippings - Re Richard M. Nixon, 1968-1971; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hoffa Biographical, 1971-1973; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Psrole Effort, 1971; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hoffa Pardon, 1971-1972; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1971-1974; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Past Pardon, 1972-1975; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Interviews Of Hoffa, 1972-1975; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - News Clippings - Teamsters Fire Hoffa's wife, Son, 1974; Series 1 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Audio/Visual Materials, 1976-1994; Series 1 (Box 9)
  - Audio/Visual Materials, 1974-1996; Series 1 (Box 10)
  - Magazines, 1937-1989; Series 1; Subseries 2
    - Detroit Free Press Magazine: Hoffa Writing the Final Chapter (3 copies), 1989 July 16; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Life Magazine, 1937 June 7; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 1 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Life Magazine, 1956 January 9; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Life Magazine, 1956 April 09; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Life Magazine, 1958 April 18; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Life Magazine: A National Threat, Hoffa's Teamsters, 1959 May 18; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Life Magazine: What Hoffa Says He'll Do, 1959 May 25; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Life Magazine: Biggest Union Gets Bigger, 1959 June 01; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Life Magazine, 1964 March 13; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Life Magazine, 1975 October 28; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Life Magazine, Winter 1976; LAC 0005 Series 1 Sub Series 2 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - GW Magazine, 2007 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Newsweek: Hoffa and the Teamsters, 1961 July 10 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Pageant: Hoffa article, 1963 August (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - People Weekly, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Picture of James P. Hoffa with Truck (3 copies), Unknown (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Playboy Hoffa Interview, 1963 November (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Washington Post: Politically Correct Teamsters, 1991 December 8 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Post, 1964 January (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Reader's Digest (two issues), 1958 November/December (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Time Magazine: Labor Boss Dave Beck, 1948 November 29 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Time Magazine, 1961 July 14 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Time Magazine, 1974 April 8 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Vanity Fair: James P. Hoffa Article, 1996 November (Box 15, Folder 17)
- Addresses and speeches, 1954-1962; Series 2
  This series contains addresses and speeches at area conferences of the Teamsters, most of which were given by James R. Hoffa. This series covers the time period from 1954 until 1962.
  - Semi-Annual Report of James R. Hoffa, Chicago, January 8, 1954, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Central States Conference of Teamsters, Semi-Annual Report of Chairman James R. Hoffa, Chicago, January 8, 1954
  - Address of James R. Hoffa, November 1959, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Central Conference of Teamsters, Address of James R. Hoffa, November 1959
  - Address by James R. Hoffa, July 1960, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Address by General President James R. Hoffa before the Over-The-Road and General hauling Trade Division, Eastern Conference of Teamsters, Atlantic City, NJ, July 7, 1960
  - Address by James R. Hoffa, March 1962, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Address by James R. Hoffa to the Eastern Conference of Teamsters, March 13, 1962
  - Address by Elmer J. Holland, March 1962, Series 2 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Address by Elmer J. Holland to the Eastern Conference of Teamsters, March 13, 1962
  - Speeches and Testimony, 1958-1966; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - James R Hoffa Resignation, 1971; Series 2 (Box 7, Folder 14)
- IBT press releases, 1962-1965; Series 3
  This series contains press releases from the Teamsters News Service, and from the Drive News Service from 1962 until 1965, many of which deal with James R. Hoffa, and the investigations and trials against him.
  - Teamsters News Service, 1962-1965; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Teamsters News Service, 1962-1965; Series 3 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- IBT publicity materials, 1956-1963; Series 4
  This series contains publicity materials about JRH issued by the IBT: two profiles, titled "The Name is Hoffa," the first published in 1956, and the second one Circa 1963.
  - The Name is Hoffa, 1956, Series 4 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    "The Name is Hoffa," IBT, Joint Council Number 13, 1956
  - The Name is Hoffa, 1963, Series 4 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    "The Name is Hoffa," IBT [1963]
- Transcript of Joint Council meeting, 1967; Series 5
  This series contains the original transcript from a Joint Council meeting in support of James R. Hoffa in March 1967, including remarks by James R. Hoffa with handwritten notes. The transcript is not entirely in order and appears to be missing some pages.
  - Transcript, JC Meeting, 1967, Series 5 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Includes an original transcript from a Joint Council meeting in support of James R. Hoffa in March 1967, including remarks by James R. Hoffa with handwritten notes. The transcript is not entirely in order and appears to be missing some pages.
- Congressional hearings and investigations, 1961-1967; Series 6
  This series contains documentation on Congressional hearings and investigations regarding JRH from 1961 until 1967, including copies from the Congressional Record, a complete transcript of hearings of a subcommittee on investigations on "Racket Control of New York City Teamster Locals" from 1961, a statement by JRH on the right to collective bargaining before the Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries and his testimony on the National Highway Safety Act (1966).
  - Hearings, U.S. Senate, 1961; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Hearings, Permanent Subcommittee on Investigations of the Office of Government Operations, United States Senate, "Racket Control of New York City Teamster Locals," vol. 5, Washington, DC, January 25, 1961.
  - Statement JRH U.S.H.R., 1963; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Congressional Records, 1963; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Copies from Congressional Record, 1964-1967
  - JRH Testimony on NHSA, 1966; Series 6 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    James Riddle Hoffa, Testimony on the National Highway Safety Act before the Senate and House Commerce Committees [1966]
  - Grand Jury Appearance NYC, 1971; Series 6 (Box 7, Folder 15)
- Trial Documentation, 1962-1966; Series 7
  This series contains documentation on trials of James R. Hoffa, including the trials in Nashville, TN, and in Chattanooga (1962-1964), as well as his trial in Chicago (1964). It includes transcripts of proceedings, testimonies, exhibits, and correspondence regarding trials and subsequent appeals up to the Supreme Court.
  - Affidavit, 1965; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    Affidavit Patsy Jo Harris, 1965
  - The Chicago Trial, 1964-1966; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    "The Chicago Trial: Ethics of Gov't Lawyers During Trial," typescript], no author [LKM?], no date, includes handwritten note by "LKM" to "S.Z." [likely Sidney Zagri].
  - Exhibit 154, 1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    US District Court, Chattanooga, TN, 2-14-1964, Exhibit 154
  - FBI Investigations, 1962-1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    Copies of FBI records from investigations against E.G. Partin, 1941-1943
  - FBI Investigations, 1965; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    Reports from the State of Alabama, Department of Toxicology and Criminal Investigation, 1965
  - "Free Hoffa" Re Pardon Requests, 1969-1971; Series 7 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - JRH - Hoffa Defense Committee, Hoffa Tesimonials, 1956, 1971; Series 7 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - JRH - Indictments, Conviction, 1963-1964; Series 7 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 1, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 2, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 3, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 4, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 5, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 6, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 7, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 8, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Hoffa Transcripts [Chattanooga Trial] Roll 9, 1964; IBT0100 Series 7 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Landrum-Griffin Violations, 1959-1966; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    Folder 20: Typescript, "Landrum-Griffin Violations," no author, no date (protest note against the way Department of Justice handled administration of Landrum-Griffin Act].
  - Lawsuit Re Retirement and Family Protection Plan, 1971; Series 7 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Legal Documents Re Pension Dispute, 1981; Series 7 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Letter Zagri to Celler, 1964; Series 7 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    Letter by Sidney Zagri to Hon. Emanuel Celler, Chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. H.R, April 15, 1964 (several copies).
  - Letter Kurland to Celler, 1964; Series 7 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    Letter by Prof. Kurland, Prof. of Law, University of Chicago, to Hon. E. Celler, Chairman of the Committee on the Judiciary, U.S. H.R, June 22, 1964.
  - Motion for New Trial, 1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    Statement Number Two. Motion for New Trial. Bias of Presiding Judge." Typescript with handwritten notes, no author, no date [1964?].
  - Motion for New Trial, 1965; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    U.S. District Court for the Eastern District of Tennessee, Southern Division, Memorandum of Law in Support of the Motion for New Trial (1965)
  - Motion to Remand to District Court, 1965; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    U.S. vs. Hoffa in the United States Court of Appeals for the Sixth Circuit, Motion for Remand to District Court, Affidavits, Exhibits, 1965
  - Outline of Response to Criticisms, 1963; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    "Outline of Response to Criticisms of the Government Regarding Trial of the Sun Valley Case,"typescript, no author, no date [1963?].
  - Partin Testimony [1/2], 1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    Testimony of E.G. Partin and many others (incl. Walter Sheridan and James R. Hoffa), and chronology of events, numerous volumes, Nashville, TN, Jan//Feb. 1964
  - Partin Testimony [2/2], 1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Report on Legal Activities, 1965; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    The International Legal Staff, Report to the General Executive Board on Legal Activities, August-September 1965
  - Statement on Immunity of Partin, 1964; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    "Statement Number One. Immunity of Partin, Much-Indicted Informer." Typescript with handwritten notes, no author, no date [1964?].
  - Summary of investigations by Congress, n.a., 1962-1966; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    Typescript, no title, author, date [contains summary of investigations by committees of Congress on "improprieties in the administration of justice in the Hoffa case."
  - Supreme Court, U.S. vs. Hoffa, 1965; Series 7 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    Supreme Court of the United States, U.S, vs. Hoffa, October 1965 (Case 794) (photocopy)
  - Supreme Court, U.S. vs. Hoffa, 1966; Series 7 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    Supreme Court of the United States, U.S. vs. Hoffa, October Term 1966.
  - U.S. vs. Hoffa, 1962; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    Transcript of Proceedings United States vs. James R. Hoffa and Commercial Carriers, Nashville, TN, Dec. 22, 1962
  - U.S. vs. Hoffa, 1963; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    U.S. vs. Hoffa, U.S. District Court for the Middle District of Tennessee, Nashville Division, Memoranda, Motions, Affidavits (1963)
  - US vs. Hoffa, Court of Appeals, 1965-1966; Series 7 (Box 5, Folder 11)